Prabhjot Singh

Junior Web Developer

Montreal, Quebec (514) 923-1226 prabhs226@gmail.com LinkedIn.com/in/prabhs226

About Me

Dynamic developer with experience in developing websites and APIs in PHP and related frameworks. Also holds a good experience in JavaScript and the jQuery framework. Always ready to learn and adapt to new and ever-changing needs of industry

PROJECTS

Currency — (Android App) (2020)

Android App to find currency exchange rates. Code written in Kotlin language. A free rate conversion API used to get the latest exchange rates. App Developed as a class project.

SBA— (API for Android App) (2017)

Backend API built in PHP using Laravel framework for android app to get, update, delete data from server. Data delivered by API in form of json objects

TheLadress — (E-Commerce website) (2016 - 2017)

An E-Commerce website focused on clothes and Accessories, developed from scratch in PHP using codeIgniter framework.

College CMS — (2015)

A simple CMS developed as a class project. Developed entirely in core php and used jQuery in the frontEnd. Main functions included Maintaining attendance, lecture details/Schedules, results and other details. Project was deployed in College to be used by the staff for a short period of time.

EDUCATION

L'institut Supérieur d'Informatique, Montreal, Quebec — P.G Diploma (Programming and Web Technologies)

2019 - Current

SKILLS

PHP, CodeIgniter, Laravel
JavaScript, Jquery, React.js
SQL
HTML5, CSS,SCSS
Android Development(Kotlin)
Java, C++,C#

STRENGTHS / VALUES

Positive Attitude
Easy Learner
Persevering
Respecting
Curious
Adaptability
Respecting

LANGUAGES

English Punjabi / Panjabi Hindi

I.K Gujral Punjab Technical University, Jalandhar, India, — B.tech (Information Technology)

2012 - 2016

EXPERIENCE

Web Developer

Creative-I Technologies, Patiala, India—Jan 2018 - Jan 2019

Tasked to write code to maintain existing code written in PHP(core and frameworks), and JavaScript.

Developer (PHP)

Trigma Solutions, Chandigarh, India—May 2016 - Nov 2017

Tasked to write code from Scratch or maintain existing code written in PHP(core and frameworks), and JavaScript

References

* Reference will be provided upon request